welcome back to AP US History in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it topic 1.5 is all about slavery
in the New World by the Spanish in my
last video I didn't go much into detail
on this but along with Goods foods and
diseases slaves were also transported
during the Colombian Exchange the reason
for this was well we first need to go
back in time when the Spanish landed in
the new world they wanted to harvest the
goods and crops of the land and
therefore decided to enslave the natives
through the encomienda system this is a
system where Spanish conquistadors were
granted the right to extract labor from
the indigenous people living in a
particular area in return the
conquistadors were to provide the
natives in this area with religious
Christian guidance and take care of
their welfare however in practice these
obligations were often neglected and
poorly fulfilled this enslaving of the
natives wouldn't end up working though
for two reasons first the nativ knew the
land that they had lived on for
centuries better than their European
guests and therefore could Escape pretty
easily
and second the natives were dying in
Mass numbers by small poox and you can't
enslave a dead person the way Spain
solved this was by transporting slaves
from Africa to the new world on ships
with the brutal Journey not as the
Middle Passage and work the land this
solved both problems because the
Africans wouldn't know the land and they
have the same natural immunity to small
poox that Europeans did with these many
Africans on the continent it allowed for
a cast system to form known as the Casta
system where Natives and Africans were
were on the bottom and anyone with
Spanish blood was on the top we'll be
going into more detail on the African
slave trade in a future video for now
that's all my friends on the screen now
are AP style questions for this topic
pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now see you in the next one